Hi, I'm Majim Rahman, a graduate
researcher from the department of
industrial engineering at the University
of Pittsburgh where I worked with Dr.
Lou and Dr. Rahimeian to recover solar
cells and bicial panels.
Solar energy is one of the fastest
growing renewable energy technologies.
However, solar panels do not last
forever.
Most modules have a lifetime of about 25
to 30 years. Then as solar deployment
continues to increase, the amount of end
of life PV waste is growing rapidly.
Many end of life panels are landfilled
and current recycling often recovers
only raw materials while destroying high
value components.
So this leads to our key research
question. Can intex silicon wafers be
recovered?
To answer this question, this work
focuses on end of life bicial glass
solar panels. These modules are
important because they feature high
efficiency cells with glass layers on
the front and the back.
The main goal is to separate the panel
layers and recover valuable materials,
especially intact silicon wafers because
they have higher use potential than
broken or fully processed silicon waste.
The key step is thermal elimination. And
during wafer recovery, samples are
heated to 500° C to remove the EVA
encapsulant and separate the panel
layers. The removal of clean EVA is
essential for the recovery of induct.
After the encapsulant is removed, it
becomes easier to separate the different
layers by allowing the recovery of
materials including glass, aluminum,
copper, and notably silicon wafers. The
experimental results revealed that
recovering intact wafers is feasible
particularly when the samples have
little or no pomech mechanical damage.
Next, we evaluated the environmental
impact using life cycle assessment. The
results indicate a significant reduction
in the cumulative energy demand when
transitioning from laboratory to
industrial scale. However, thermal
treatment remains the dominant energy
contributor.
Finally, we evaluated the physibility of
the strategy from an economic
standpoint. The analysis shows that
recovered wafers can reduce model
manufacturing cost from 10.5 cents per
watt peak to 9.2 cents per watt peak.
And when more than half of the wafers
are fully recovered, the technique
becomes commercially viable.
So our study shows that end ofly bfacial
solar panels can be transformed into
valuable sources of recoverable glass
and metals as well as reusable silicon
wafers supporting circular economic
principles. So in summary, end of life
solar panels do not have to become the
waste. They have the potential to serve
as valuable assets for future solar
module development.
Thank